Reg Manning Papers
Reg Manning Papers
1941-1969
1954-1964
Manning, Reg, 1905-1986
21.8 linear ft.
Approximately 2,600 original editorial cartoons syndicated through the McNaught Syndicate and published locally in the Arizona Republic and artwork for single panel cartoons, Little Itchy Itchy, The Little Savage, The Ordinary Americans and Oh Say Can You See--?. Correspondence, book illustrations and articles about Manning are also included.
149148
Biographical History
Reginald Manning (1905-1986) was a Pulitzer Prize winning American editorial cartoonist.
Born April 8, 1905 in Kansas City, Missouri, Reg Manning moved to Phoenix, Arizona in 1919 with his brother and their widowed mother. While in high school, Manning received his only formal art training and drew cartoons. After graduation, he pursued freelance work for two years before being hired as an artist and photographer at the Arizona Republic in 1926 (then the Arizona Republican), replacing Webb Smith.
At first Manning drew few editorial cartoons and instead focused on a full page Sunday current events cartoon, "The Big Parade" which appeared from October 1926 through April 1948. It included a variety of elements commenting on local issues as well as other features including Traffic Jam, a safety cartoon, Ruff Riter, and the Snooper’s Dirt Diary. Manning wanted work as a comic strip artist but his editorial cartoons proved more popular and newspapers across the United States began to reprint them. In 1937 Manning became affiliated with the McNaught Syndicate and his cartoons would eventually appear in over 125 newspapers. Manning worked out of his home and with McNaught's mailing center in Arizona to produce six cartoons a week while he also contributed a weekly cartoon to the Arizona Republic. Manning's work was well known as having an openly conservative tone.
In 1951 Manning received the Pulitzer Prize for one of his cartoons about the Korean War, "Hats". Also in May of that year, "Reg Manning Day" was held at Arizona State University with Barry Goldwater as the master of ceremonies. This event honored 25 years of Manning's work. Manning traveled giving chalk talks to soldiers and spoke as part of several college and university lecture series. He also served on the board of the Desert Botanical Garden of Arizona and was a member of the National Cartoonists Society as well as the Arizona Press Club, the Phoenix Press Club and the American Association of Editorial Cartoonists. The United States Treasury Department gave Manning a citation for his efforts to promote savings bonds.
Manning also received over a dozen awards from Freedoms Foundation, the 1957 National Safety Council Award and the Abraham Lincoln Award in 1971 and 1972. Manning's b books include two books about Arizona, The Cartoon Guide to Arizona (1938) and What Kinda Cactus Izzat? (1941), a guide to desert plants in the southwest. He also illustrated From Tee to Cup (1954) and a compilation of his cartoons was published in 1980 as Best of Reg. His other artistic work included jewelry, stationary, watercolor paintings and fabric designs.
Manning worked for the Arizona Republic for over 50 years and reduced his work load in 1980. Reginald Manning died in Phoenix, Arizona on March 10, 1986.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Reg Manning Papers are divided into four series consisting of original cartoon artwork and illustrations, published material, biographical material and correspondence.
The Original Artwork series (1941-1964) contains primarily editorial cartoons published by the Arizona Republic and syndicated by the McNaught Syndicate but also single panel cartoons and book illustrations.
There are approximately 2,607 original editorial cartoons, 2,194 of which were syndicated and approximately 413 for local publication in the Arizona Republic. Typically a separate local cartoon appeared in the Arizona Republic, while Manning produced other cartoons specifically for the McNaught Syndicate. However, it appears several cartoons may have been used in both as they are labeled "Republic" but also bear a sticker from the McNaught Syndicate.
Several recurring characters and themes can be found in Manning’s work such as Uno Who, a man representing the average American taxpayer. Manning expressed thoughts about how the government works under the title "The Wizards of Washington". At the end of each year, Manning produced a cartoon tying together major events of the year and his April Fool's Day cartoons joked about unlikely events and political partnerships. Manning also regularly drew cartoons about fatal automobile accidents around the holidays to promote traffic and highway safety.
Manning's local cartoons addressed issues including struggles with California to obtain Colorado River water, property taxes, the appeal of Arizona as a snowbird destination, Arizona’s soaring population and the growth of Phoenix through annexation.
The cartoons were drawn with pen, ink and crayon on illustration board and measure approximately 11" x 14 1/2". Captions appear in heavy black ink at the top. Syndicated cartoons bear the name of the McNaught Syndicate. Manning mailed in cartoons several in advance of their scheduled publication. Please note, the date on the cartoon is the date on which it was scheduled to be mailed, not necessarily the publication date. Because Manning produced cartoons several days in advance, there are several cartoons in the collection that were not published, according to notations, because they were no longer timely. On some cartoons, Manning gave instructions to the syndicate to alter the cartoon depending on election outcomes. See cartoons from July 1960 for examples of this. Also of interest is a cartoon about John Glenn's space orbit which was to only be published if the mission was successful. The date of publication for cartoons appearing in the Arizona Republic is written on the local cartoons.
Also included is approximately 280 pieces of original artwork, 11" x 14 1/2" in size, from four different single panel cartoons, Little Itchy-Itchy (1945), The Little Savage (1946-1949), The Ordinary Americans (1954-1955), and Oh Say Can You See (1961-1963). Little Itchy-Itchy depicted the Japanese during World War II. The Ordinary Americans profiled average people holding various occupations. Oh Say Can You See--? illustrated patriotic themes. There are illustrations done in ink (traces of pencil are visible) from the book From Tee to Cup which measure approximately 14 1/2" x 23".
Correspondence (1954) contains letters from readers including ordinary citizens and businessmen. The correspondence is typically about Manning’s series, The Ordinary Americans. Correspondents include a miner who disagrees with Manning’s portrayal of salesmen, a unionized waitress and an 80 year old woman. Several copies of cartoons are attached to correspondence.
Biographical material consists of a typed biography of Manning as well as one photograph. Both are undated.
Published material (1954-1969) contains several newspaper and magazine articles about Manning and material related to From Tee to Cup.
Arrangement of the Collection
Original artwork is divided into cartoons and illustrations. Editorial cartoons arranged chronologically but separated within each year by type of cartoon- those published locally in the Arizona Republic and syndicated cartoons. Panel cartoons are divided by title are also arranged in chronological order. Illustrations for From Tee to Cup are in page order number.
Related Material
has the papers of more than a hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
The following items have been removed from the collection and transferred to Rare Books:
From Tee to Cup (1954)
Little Itchy Itchy, and other cartoons (1944)
Best of Reg (1980)
Reg Manning's desert in crystal: photographs of the artist's copper wheel (1973)
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Manning, Reg, 1905-1986 -- Archives.; Gaulle, Charles de, 1890-1970 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Fannin, Paul J. (Paul Jones), 1907-2002 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Goldwater, Barry, 1938- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Macmillan, Harold, 1894-1986 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Castro, Fidel, 1926- -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; McNaught Syndicate.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United Nations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress. -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Little itchy itchy.; Little savage.; Oh say can you see?; Ordinary Americans.; Arizona republic.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Traffic fatalities -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cities and towns -- Growth -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Arms race -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cartoonists -- Arizona.; Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- Arizona.; Editorial cartoons -- Phoenix (Ariz.); Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Pulitzer Prizes.; Water rights -- Arizona.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Drawings (visual works); Editorial cartoons.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Reg Manning, 1964, 1973, 1985.
Inventory
- Original Artwork
  - Editorial cartoons, 11" x 14 1/2"; Click here for a detailed inventory.
    - 1941 Jan, 1944 Nov, 1945 Mar-Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - 1945 May-Aug, 1945 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    - 1947 Jun-Jul (local) (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
    - 1947 Mar-Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    - 1948 Feb, 1948 Apr-Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
    - 1948 Nov-Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
    - 1949 Mar (local) (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
    - 1949 Jan-Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 8)
    - 1949 Jul-Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 9)
    - 1949 Apr-Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 10)
    - 1949 Oct-Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 1, Folder 11)
    - 1950 Jan-Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
    - 1950 May-Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
    - 1950 Aug (local) (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
    - 1950 Sep-Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
    - 1951 Jan-Feb, 1951 Apr, 1951 Jun, 1951 Aug, 1951 Nov (local) (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
    - 1951 Jan-Feb, 1951 Apr-May (syndicated) (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
    - 1951 Jun-Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
    - 1951 Aug-Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 2, Folder 8)
    - 1951 Oct-Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 2, Folder 9)
    - 1952 Jan-Mar, 1952 May-Jul, 1952 Oct (local) (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
    - 1952 Jan-Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
    - 1952 Apr-Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
    - 1952 Jul-Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
    - 1952 Oct-Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
    - 1953 Jan, 1953 Mar, 1953 Jun, 1953 Sep-Oct, 1953 Dec (local) (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
    - 1953 Jan-Apr, 1953 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    - 1954 Jan, 1954 Mar-May, 1954 Sep-Nov (local) (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
    - 1954 Jan-Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - 1954 May-Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - 1955 Jan, 1955 Apr-May, 1955 Jul, 1955 Nov (local) (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
    - 1955 Jan-Mar, 1955 May-Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
    - 1955 Aug-Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
    - 1956 Feb-Apr, 1956 Jun-Dec (local) (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
    - 1956 Jan-Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
    - 1956 Apr-May (syndicated) (Oversize 4, Folder 6)
    - 1956 Jun-Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 4, Folder 7)
    - 1956 Aug-Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
    - 1956 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
    - 1956 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
    - 1956 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
    - 1956 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
    - 1957 Jan-May (local) (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
    - 1957 Jun-Sep (local) (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
    - 1957 Oct-Dec (local) (Oversize 5, Folder 8)
    - 1957 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
    - 1957 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
    - 1957 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
    - 1957 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
    - 1957 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
    - 1957 May (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 6)
    - 1957 May (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 7)
    - 1957 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 6, Folder 8)
    - 1957 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
    - 1957 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
    - 1957 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
    - 1957 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
    - 1957 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 5)
    - 1957 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 6)
    - 1957 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 7)
    - 1957 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 8)
    - 1957 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 9)
    - 1957 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 7, Folder 10)
    - 1957 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
    - 1957 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
    - 1958 Jan-May (local) (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
    - 1958 Jun-Sep (local) (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
    - 1958 Oct-Dec (local) (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
    - 1958 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
    - 1958 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
    - 1958 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
    - 1958 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
    - 1958 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
    - 1958 May (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
    - 1958 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
    - 1958 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
    - 1958 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 7)
    - 1958 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 9, Folder 8)
    - 1958 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 1)
    - 1958 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 2)
    - 1958 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 3)
    - 1958 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 4)
    - 1958 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 5)
    - 1958 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 6)
    - 1958 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 7)
    - 1958 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 10, Folder 8)
    - 1959 Jan-Apr (local) (Oversize 11, Folder 1)
    - 1959 May-Sep (local) (Oversize 11, Folder 2)
    - 1959 Oct-Dec (local) (Oversize 11, Folder 3)
    - 1959 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 11, Folder 4)
    - 1959 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 11, Folder 5)
    - 1959 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 11, Folder 6)
    - 1959 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 11, Folder 7)
    - 1959 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 11, Folder 8)
    - 1959 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 1)
    - 1959 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 2)
    - 1959 May (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 3)
    - 1959 May (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 4)
    - 1959 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 5)
    - 1959 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 6)
    - 1959 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 7)
    - 1959 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 12, Folder 8)
    - 1959 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 1)
    - 1959 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 2)
    - 1959 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 3)
    - 1959 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 4)
    - 1959 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 5)
    - 1959 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 6)
    - 1959 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 7)
    - 1959 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 13, Folder 8)
    - 1959 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 14, Folder 1)
    - 1959 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 14, Folder 2)
    - 1960 Jan-Apr (local) (Oversize 14, Folder 3)
    - 1960 May-Aug (local) (Oversize 14, Folder 4)
    - 1960 Sep-Dec (local) (Oversize 14, Folder 5)
    - 1960 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 14, Folder 6)
    - 1960 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 14, Folder 7)
    - 1960 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 14, Folder 8)
    - 1960 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 1)
    - 1960 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 2)
    - 1960 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 3)
    - 1960 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 4)
    - 1960 May (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 5)
    - 1960 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 6)
    - 1960 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 7)
    - 1960 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 15, Folder 8)
    - 1960 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 1)
    - 1960 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 2)
    - 1960 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 3)
    - 1960 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 4)
    - 1960 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 5)
    - 1960 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 6)
    - 1960 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 7)
    - 1960 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 16, Folder 8)
    - 1961 Jan-Mar (local) (Oversize 17, Folder 1)
    - 1961 Apr-Jul (local) (Oversize 17, Folder 2)
    - 1961 Aug-Dec (local) (Oversize 17, Folder 3)
    - 1961 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 17, Folder 4)
    - 1961 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 17, Folder 5)
    - 1961 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 17, Folder 6)
    - 1961 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 17, Folder 7)
    - 1961 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 1)
    - 1961 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 2)
    - 1961 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 3)
    - 1961 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 4)
    - 1961 May (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 5)
    - 1961 May (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 6)
    - 1961 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 7)
    - 1961 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 18, Folder 8)
    - 1961 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 1)
    - 1961 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 2)
    - 1961 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 3)
    - 1961 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 4)
    - 1961 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 5)
    - 1961 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 6)
    - 1961 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 7)
    - 1961 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 19, Folder 8)
    - 1961 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 20, Folder 1)
    - 1961 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 20, Folder 2)
    - 1961 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 20, Folder 3)
    - 1961 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 20, Folder 4)
    - 1962 Jan-May (local) (Oversize 20, Folder 5)
    - 1962 Jun-Jul (local) (Oversize 20, Folder 6)
    - 1962 Aug-Sep (local) (Oversize 20, Folder 7)
    - 1962 Oct-Dec (local) (Oversize 20, Folder 8)
    - 1962 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 1)
    - 1962 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 2)
    - 1962 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 3)
    - 1962 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 4)
    - 1962 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 5)
    - 1962 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 6)
    - 1962 May (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 7)
    - 1962 May (syndicated) (Oversize 21, Folder 8)
    - 1962 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 1)
    - 1962 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 2)
    - 1962 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 3)
    - 1962 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 4)
    - 1962 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 5)
    - 1962 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 6)
    - 1962 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 7)
    - 1962 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 8)
    - 1962 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 9)
    - 1962 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 22, Folder 10)
    - 1962 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 23, Folder 1)
    - 1962 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 23, Folder 2)
    - 1962 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 23, Folder 3)
    - 1962 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 23, Folder 4)
    - 1963 Jan-Feb (local) (Oversize 23, Folder 5)
    - 1963 Mar-Apr (local) (Oversize 23, Folder 6)
    - 1963 May-Jul (local) (Oversize 23, Folder 7)
    - 1963 Aug-Oct (local) (Oversize 23, Folder 8)
    - 1963 Nov-Dec (local) (Oversize 24, Folder 1)
    - 1963 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 2)
    - 1963 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 3)
    - 1963 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 4)
    - 1963 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 5)
    - 1963 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 6)
    - 1963 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 7)
    - 1963 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 8)
    - 1964 May (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 9)
    - 1964 May (syndicated) (Oversize 24, Folder 10)
    - 1963 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 1)
    - 1963 Jun (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 2)
    - 1963 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 3)
    - 1963 Jul (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 4)
    - 1963 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 5)
    - 1963 Aug (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 6)
    - 1963 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 7)
    - 1963 Sep (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 8)
    - 1963 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 9)
    - 1963 Oct (syndicated) (Oversize 25, Folder 10)
    - 1963 Nov (syndicated) (Oversize 26, Folder 1)
    - 1963 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 26, Folder 2)
    - 1963 Dec (syndicated) (Oversize 26, Folder 3)
    - 1964 Jan-Apr (local) (Oversize 26, Folder 4)
    - 1964 Jan (syndicated) (Oversize 26, Folder 5)
    - 1964 Feb (syndicated) (Oversize 26, Folder 6)
    - 1964 Mar (syndicated) (Oversize 26, Folder 7)
    - 1964 Apr (syndicated) (Oversize 26, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons (single panel), 11" x 14 1/2" 280 items
    - Little Itchy Itchy, 1945; Click here for a detailed inventory.; 17 items (Oversize 27)
    - The Little Savage, 1946-1949; Click here for a detailed inventory.; 79 items (Oversize 27)
    - Oh Say Can You See--?, 1961-1963; Click here for a detailed inventory.; 122 items (Oversize 28)
    - The Ordinary Americans, 1954-1955; Click here for a detailed inventory.; 72 items (Oversize 27)
  - Illustrations
    - From Tee to Cup, circa 1954; 49 items; pages 1, 4-7, 9-19, 23-43, 45-47, 55-57, 59-60, 62-63, 66-69, 71-72, 74-79, 81-87, 90-95, 100-112 (Oversize 29)
- Biographical Material
  - Photograph and typed biography, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming correspondence, 1954 (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Articles (Box 1)
    Arizona Republic 75th Anniversary section - May 16, 1965
    Front page of Arizona Republic with "Ordinary Americans" cartoon- January 11, 1954
    Front page of Arizona Republic with "Ordinary Americans" cartoon- January 18, 1954
    "L.B.J. & Reg"- May 28, 1954
    Review of Manning's book What is Arizona Like from Arizona Highways- February 1969
  - Clipping of color cartoon from the Arizona Republic, 1963 Jul 4 (Box 1)
  - From Tee to Cup illustrations, 1954; with note of explanation from Manning (Box 1)
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, For example: B1= Box 1
abortion B20
Acheson, Dean B2 B19
Adams, Sherman B9 B26
Adenauer, Konrad B4 B7 B12-B13 B18-B19 B21-B22 B24-B25
Afghanistan B12
AFL-CIO B1 B4-B11 B19-B20
Africa B4-B5 B8-B10 B12 B14-B18 B24-B26
airline industry B10-B11
Alabama B18 B24
Alaska B9 B11-B12 B26
Albania B19
Aleman, Miguel B1
Algeria B4 B7 B9 B13-B14 B16 B18 B21-B22 B25
American Indians B2 B5 B11 B23
Americans for Democratic Action B15 B26
anti-missile systems B8 B26
anti-Semitism B14